I read the first edition of this book early in 1950, when I was nine- 
teen. I thought then that it was by far the best book about investing 
ever written. I still think it is. 
To invest successfully over a lifetime does not require a strato- 
spheric IQ, unusual business insights, or inside information. 
What's needed is a sound intellectual framework for making deci- 
sions and the ability to keep emotions from corroding that frame- 
work. This book precisely and clearly prescribes the proper 
framework. You must supply the emotional discipline. 
If you follow the behavioral and business principles that Gra- 
ham advocates—and if you pay special attention to the invaluable 
advice in Chapters 8 and 20—you will not get a poor result from 
your investments. (That represents more of an accomplishment 
than you might think.) Whether you achieve outstanding results 
will depend on the effort and intellect you apply to your invest- 
ments, as well as on the amplitudes of stock-market folly that pre- 
Vail during your investing career. The sillier the market's behavior, 
the greater the opportunity for the business-like investor. Follow 
Graham and you will profit from folly rather than participate in it. 
To me, Ben Graham was far more than an author or a teacher. 
More than any other man except my father, he influenced my life. 
Shortly after Ben's death in 1976, I wrote the following short 
remembrance about him in the Financial Analysts Journal. As you 
read the book, I believe you'll perceive some of the qualities I men- 
tioned in this tribute. 


